Ryan Palm

(808) 292 – 8628 | ryan.c.palm@outlook.com

Introduction

My experience as a Damage Controlman in the United States Coast Guard partnered with my lifelong experience in the IT field has allowed me to develop a highly effective, unique, and valuable skill set.

Kev Skills

<u>Problem Solving</u> – Solves complex problems through methodical processes both independently and in conjunction with others to provide efficient and high-quality resolutions.

<u>Teamwork</u> – Award winning teamwork skills. Enjoys working with others and sharing knowledge to encourage the success and development of other team members, as well as team goals.

<u>Communication</u> – Trained in and employs active listening and thoughtful questioning to ensure high quality and successful communication. Trained in technical writing.

Experience

IT Consultant and Contractor Greater Seattle Area (2015 – present)

Contracting work for numerous clients to provide a broad range of IT solutions and services.

- Routinely provide support, diagnostic, and troubleshooting services for windows-based workstations and other IT related devices.
- Deploy and configure workstations, servers, IP security cameras, networking hardware, and other various business-related IT hardware to support business operations.
- Routinely provide operating system and other software related installation, configuration, and troubleshooting services.

Consultant, Contractor, Volunteer at Historic Hawaii Foundation (2010 – 2013)

Provided IT solutions and support for business operations for this non-profit organization.

- Designed and implemented an offsite backup solution for web server and internal databases.
- Provided consultant services for the procurement of new computers and office hardware.
- Provided website maintenance and administration services.
- Provided troubleshooting and diagnostic services for workstations and server.

Third Class Damage Controlman, United States Coast Guard (2006 – 2010)

Honorable discharge. Obtained the following awards: Coast Guard Meritorious Team Commendation Ribbon, Coast Guard Good Conduct Medal, Coast Guard "E" Ribbon.

- Plumbing, pipe fitting, welding, oxyfuel cutting/brazing, metal work, rough carpentry, and construction.
- Lead firefighting and flooding teams in ship emergencies and training.
- Provided onboard safety and emergency briefings and training to large audiences.
- Maintained excellent shipboard organization and cleanliness day in and day out.

Education

<u>Bachelor of Arts, Major in Applied Computing, Minor in Consciousness Studies</u> – 3.8 GPA University of Washington Bothell (2015 – 2019)

Associate in Integrated Studies

Cascadia Community College (2014 – 2015)